<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Soul Care]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/</link><image><url>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Soul Care</title><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/</link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 12:08:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 12:08:44 GMT</pubDate><copyright><![CDATA[Aleeza Chery]]></copyright><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator>Aleeza Chery</dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Concept 1 - Introduction]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br> Clean &amp; Pure: An Introduction to Soul Care - Concept 1 - The Proposal
	
		
			Concept 1
		
    
  
<br>Have you ever been submerged into the water? That is—been baptized? It may be fresh in your mind because it was a pivotal moment in your life or because it happened not too long ago. For some, it may be distant, literally, because of how long ago it occurred or maybe, distant in the sense that it was not that special; just part of the process of the duties of a Christian life.<br>The purpose of exploring this concept is to propose a view of baptism that will refresh or even totally shift your perspective—of you: How heaven sees you, what you are truly capable of and the union you are called to with Christ. Unlike baptism, which is the symbol of this transformation, this leg of the journey—the counseling process mentioned in the introduction—is not instantaneous. What will be instantaneous, however, is the change in your perspective, whose power should never be underestimated as a motivating factor. Your perspective will not shift however, unless you've accepted two things. It is absolutely necessary to believe that 1) this journey, this way He is taking you, is the only way, and, 2) the only way is up—that is, superior to where you are now.<br>Before we can see that, let us look at various excerpts of scripture with fresh eyes, which can show us where we came from and where we are going.<br>
  
    Do you remember reading comprehension in grade school? The teacher would give a text and there would be questions after and all of the answers would be pulled from the text? And then if you ever got stuck on a question, the teacher would have you go back to the text? For the purpose of this study–biblical based strengthening of the foundation of our faith–after each reading, there are discussion prompt questions to help us dig deeper, but simply in our understanding of scripture. Please do your best to answer the questions as simply as you can based on the text given and not any prior knowledge you may have, even if it's biblical.
  
]]></description><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/the-kings-college/concept-1/concept-1-introduction.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">the-kings-college/Concept 1/Concept 1 - Introduction.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aleeza Chery]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 12:08:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Concept 1 - Unit 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br> Clean &amp; Pure: An Introduction to Soul Care - Concept 1 - The Proposal
	
    		
    Genesis 6:3-14, 22 ESV
  
<br><br>Leading up to Genesis 6, Yahweh God has not too long ago created the earth in all it's splendor and beauty with perfectly pure human beings Adam and Eve. Just 5 chapters away from that, after the pair committed the first sin, the entire world has gone wrong and corruption is throughout.<br>
    While reading this passage, we will underline every reference to a man, his flesh or &nbsp;heart; a triangle for every reference for God, his heart or his feelings, including pronouns; a circle for every reference for God's Spirit, and a heart for every reference for Noah, including descriptors and pronouns.
	
			&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Genesis+6%3A3-14%2C22&amp;version=ESV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Genesis 6:3-14,22 ESV</a>
    
		
		
			
				
          
            man/flesh
					
					
            God
					
					
            God's Spirit
					
					
            Noah
					
				
			
			
				
          
						3 Then the Lord said, “My Spirit shall not abide in man forever, for he is flesh: his days shall be 120 years.” 4 The Nephilim were on the earth in those days, and also afterward, when the sons of God came in to the daughters of man and they bore children to them. These were the mighty men who were of old, the men of renown. 
					
					
						5 The Lord saw that the wickedness of man was great in the earth, and that every intention of the thoughts of his heart was only evil continually. 6 And the Lord regretted that he had made man on the earth, and it grieved him to his heart.
					
					
						9 These are the generations of Noah.
					
					
            Noah was a righteous man, blameless in his generation. Noah walked with God. 10&nbsp;Bnd Noah had three sons, Shem, Ham, and Japheth. 11 Now the earth was corrupt in God’s sight, and the earth was filled with violence.12 And God saw the earth, and behold, it was corrupt, for all flesh had corrupted their way on the earth. 13 And God said to Noah, “I have determined to make an end of all flesh, for the earth is filled with violence through them. Behold, I will destroy them with the earth. 14 Make yourself an ark of gopher wood. Make rooms in the ark, and cover it inside and out with pitch.* 22 Noah did this; he did all that God commanded him.
					
           * 14-21 God describes to Noah the details of the boat to be built.
				
			
		
  
			&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Genesis+6%3A3-14%2C22&amp;version=ESV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Genesis 6:3-14,22 ESV</a>
    
 
  Please do your best to answer the questions as simply as you can based on the text given and not any prior knowledge you may have, even if it's biblical. <br><br>Questions with asterisks* may inquire about general definitions and meaning not found in the text, for those you may use your common knowledge.

  
<br>
<br>From what we can gather from the text, what was God experiencing on account of what His world had become? (v. 6)
<br>
<br>What was occurring that made Him feel this way? (v. 5)
<br>
<br>What is the contrast between Noah and the rest of the world? (v. 9, v. 12)
<br>
<br>How does God feel about Noah? (v. 8)
<br>
<br>What does Noah's presence on the earth do for God's perspective of it? (v. 9)
<br>&nbsp;<br><br>
    
      <a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Genesis+6%3A3-14%2C22&amp;version=ESV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Genesis 6:3-14,22 ESV</a>
    
  
<br>
<br>What might it have been like for Noah to be so different and to be the only one?
<br>
<br>In light of God's ability to do anything, i.e., pull Noah into heaven and create a new earth, what do you think God is doing by having Noah be the one to build the ark?
<br>
<br>Can you think of a time when God required your participation in something He was doing for you?
]]></description><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/the-kings-college/concept-1/concept-1-unit-1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">the-kings-college/Concept 1/Concept 1 - Unit 1.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aleeza Chery]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:23:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Concept 1 - Unit 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br> Clean &amp; Pure: An Introduction to Soul Care - Concept 1 - The Proposal
	
    		
    1 Peter 3:8-22 Various Translations
  
<br><br>In this scripture we find ourselves smack dab in the middle of the 1st century after Christ's death, burial and resurrection. According to church history, in Rome, on July 18 the year 64, a massive fire breaks out, which rages for 9 days and destroys 71% of the city. In order to find someone to blame, Nero, the emperor at this time, pins the cause of the fire on Christians, after which a harsh persecution begins. Peter sends a letter to the various groups of Christians spread about in what is known as present day Turkey. This letter, which we call 1 Peter in our scriptures, warns them of the coming persecution, but encourages them to stay the course. This particular passage prompts them and us to remember the foundation of salvation, especially when times get hard.<br>
    While reading this passage, we will underline every reference to a man, his flesh or heart; a triangle for every reference for God, his heart or his feelings, including pronouns; a cross for &nbsp;Christ; a circle for every reference for God's Spirit, and a heart for every reference for Noah or you (what can be considered you), including descriptors and pronouns.
	
				&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=1+Peter+3%3A8-22&amp;version=NASB;NIV;ESV;HCSB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1 Peter 3:8-22 Various Translations</a>
    
		
		
			
				
          
            man/flesh
					
					
            God
					
          
            Christ
					
					
            God's Spirit
					
					
            Noah/You
					
				
			
			
				
          
						8 Finally, all of you, be like-minded, be sympathetic, love one another, be compassionate and humble. 9 Do not repay evil with evil or insult with insult. On the contrary, repay evil with blessing, because to this you were called so that you may inherit a blessing. 
					
          
            10 For
            Whoever desires to love life<br> and see good days,<br> let him keep his tongue from evil<br>  and his lips from speaking deceit;<br>  11 let him turn away from evil and do good;<br>  let him seek peace and pursue it.<br>12 For the eyes of the Lord are on the righteous, <br>and his ears are open to their prayer.<br>But the face of the Lord is against those who do evil.(quoted from Psalms)
          
          
            13 Who is going to harm you if you are eager to do good? 14 But even if you should suffer for what is right, you are blessed. “Do not fear their threats; do not be frightened.” 15 But in your hearts revere Christ as Lord. Always be prepared to give an answer to everyone who asks you to give the reason for the hope that you have. But do this with gentleness and respect, 16 keeping a clear conscience, so that those who speak maliciously against your good behavior in Christ may be ashamed of their slander. 17 For it is better, if it is God’s will, to suffer for doing good than for doing evil.  
					
					
             18 For Christ also suffered once for sins, the righteous for the unrighteous, that he might bring us to God, being put to death in the flesh but made alive in the spirit,19 in which he went and proclaimed to the spirits in prison, 20 because they formerly did not obey, when God's patience waited in the days of Noah, while the ark was being prepared, in which a few, that is, eight persons, were brought safely through water.
          
          
            21 Baptism, which corresponds to this, now saves you (not the removal of the filth of the flesh, but the pledge of a good conscience toward God) through the resurrection of Jesus Christ. 22 Now that He has gone into heaven, He is at God’s right hand with angels, authorities, and powers subject to Him. 
					
        
			
		
   
  
  					&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=1+Peter+3%3A8-22&amp;version=NASB;NIV;ESV;HCSB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1 Peter 3:8-22 Various Translations</a>
    
 
  Please do your best to answer the questions as simply as you can based on the text given and not any prior knowledge you may have, even if it's biblical. <br><br>Questions with asterisks* may inquire about general definitions and meaning not found in the text, for those you may use your common knowledge.

  
<br>
<br>Who was actually submerged under the water during the time of Noah in the flood? What happened to them?
<br>
<br>In verse 18 it says, "For Christ also suffered once for sins, the righteous for the unrighteous," Thinking about the people of the flood, why did Christ have to suffer and die for people to be saved?
<br>
<br>In our previous scripture, Genesis 6, it states, “Noah was a righteous man, blameless in his generation. Noah walked with God.” If Noah was saved based on this criteria, at that time, would we have been submerged or in the boat?
<br>
<br>Verse 21 says that baptism corresponds to what happened in the days of Noah. Make a comparison list of the "baptism" during Noah's time and the symbolic act that is performed today. 
<br>Terms from the scripture (v18-20) to compare:<br>
<br>&nbsp;<br><br>
    
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=1+Peter+3%3A8-22&amp;version=NASB;NIV;ESV;HCSB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1 Peter 3:8-22 Various Translations</a>
    
  
<br>
<br>What is God saying about your value to make this kind of exchange mentioned in verse18?
<br>In our previous scripture Genesis 6:3-14,22, it only states that Noah, was righteous, blameless and walked with God, why do you think the other 7 people were saved?
<br>In verse 21, what does "the pledge of a good conscience toward God" mean?
<br>Had your current view of baptism included the back story of Noah and the Flood?
]]></description><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/the-kings-college/concept-1/concept-1-unit-2.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">the-kings-college/Concept 1/Concept 1 - Unit 2.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aleeza Chery]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:23:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Concept 1 - Unit 3]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br> Clean &amp; Pure: An Introduction to Soul Care - Concept 1 - The Proposal
	
    		
    Matthew 3:11–4:1 ESV
  
<br><br>This scripture is taken from the account of Jesus' life written by Matthew, one of His close disciples turned apostle. A figure named John the Baptist has devoted his life to living in the desert, eating locusts and wild honey, and immersing sinners into water as a sign of repentance, at the direction of God. He is also spreading the message about the coming of Jesus, which he believes he will see. At this point in the scripture, John has just rebuked the Israeli religious leaders who have come to join in on this sacred display, because of their lack of sincerity.<br>
		While reading this passage, we will put a triangle for every reference for &nbsp;God, his &nbsp;heart or his &nbsp;feelings, including pronouns; a cross for &nbsp;Jesus including pronouns; a circle for the&nbsp;Holy Spirit including pronouns; a heart around every reference for&nbsp;you or any &nbsp;followers of Christ, including descriptors and plural pronouns, and underline every reference for&nbsp;fire.
	
				&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Matthew%203%3A11%E2%80%934%3A1&amp;version=ESV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Matthew 3:11–4:1 ESV</a>
    
		
		
			
				
					
						God
					
					
						God's Spirit
					
					
						Christ
					
				
						You
					
          
		  	fire
					
				
			
			
				
					
            
							3
						
					11 “I baptize you with water for repentance, but he who is coming after me is mightier than I, whose sandals I am not worthy to carry. He will baptize you with the Holy Spirit and fire.
             12&nbsp;His winnowing fork is in his hand, and he will clear his threshing floor and gather his wheat into the barn, but the chaff he will burn with unquenchable fire.”
            13&nbsp;Then Jesus came from Galilee to the Jordan to John, to be baptized by him. 14&nbsp;John would have prevented him, saying, “I need to be baptized by you, and do you come to me?” 15&nbsp;But Jesus answered him, “Let it be so now, for thus it is fitting for us to fulfill all righteousness.” Then he consented. 16&nbsp;And when Jesus was baptized, immediately he went up from the water, and behold, the heavens were opened to him, and he saw the Spirit of God descending like a dove and coming to rest on him; 17&nbsp;and behold, a voice from heaven said, “This is my beloved Son, with whom I am well pleased.”
          
          
            
							4
						
            1 Then Jesus was led up by the Spirit into the wilderness to be tempted by the devil.
          
        
			
		
  
  					&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Matthew%203%3A11%E2%80%934%3A1&amp;version=ESV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Matthew 3:11–4:1 ESV</a>
    
 
  Please do your best to answer the questions as simply as you can based on the text given and not any prior knowledge you may have, even if it's biblical. <br><br>Questions with asterisks* may inquire about general definitions and meaning not found in the text, for those you may use your common knowledge.

  
<br>
<br>
According to this text, what was the reason for John's baptism with water? (3:11)

<br>
What requires <a data-href="repentance" href="https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/definitions/repentance.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">repentance</a>? What is the reason for people to <a data-href="repent" href="https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/definitions/repent.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">repent</a> before God?*

<br>
Why do you think John was trying to prevent Jesus from being baptized? (3:14)

<br>
What is Jesus doing by submitting to the baptism of repentance? (3:15)

<br>
According to this text, what are the two parts of the baptism Jesus baptizes us with? (3:11)

<br>
What analogy does John use to describe the baptism of the Holy Spirit and fire? (3:12)

<br>
Does the second mention of fire give us an explanation of the first mention of fire?

<br>
What needs to happen first before the baptism of the Holy Spirit and of Fire?

<br>
After the Spirit is seen coming over Jesus, what does the Spirit have him do? (4:1)

<br>
Which part of the baptism of the Holy Spirit and fire do you see happen to Jesus at His baptism of repentance? (3:16)

<br>&nbsp;<br><br>
    
      <a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Matthew%203%3A11%E2%80%934%3A1&amp;version=ESV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Matthew 3:11–4:1 ESV</a>
    
  
<br>
<br>
Is the winnowing fork process mandatory for the baptism of Holy Spirit and of Fire?

<br>
If Yeshua's winnowing for is about sanctification, how can I use the experience of His baptism and His subsequent process in the wilderness to navigate my own process?

]]></description><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/the-kings-college/concept-1/concept-1-unit-3.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">the-kings-college/Concept 1/Concept 1 - Unit 3.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aleeza Chery]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 08:56:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Concept 1 - Unit 4]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br> Clean &amp; Pure: An Introduction to Soul Care - Concept 1 - The Proposal
	
    		
    Romans 6:4-14 NIV
  
<br><br>This letter written by Paul—his longest in the New Testament—was sent ahead to the city of Rome around the year AD 57, to a church he had never visited before, to people he didn't know. Some years before this letter, the booming church in Rome, which was mostly populated by Jewish converts, was emptied by the Roman Emperor Claudius, when he threw all Jews out of Rome because of their quarreling over a leader named, "Chrestus." Their exile was short lived and Jews were invited back into the city by the next emperor, but by then the population of the gentile believers in the area had grown significantly. This letter speaks on the differences and issues between Jewish and Gentile Christians. Paul makes many appeals to their spiritual natures to dismiss their national and cultural allegiances, with a desire to see them united in brotherly love. We zone in on Chapter 6, where Paul is discussing the aspects of a believer's union with Christ.<br>
    While reading this passage, we will put a triangle for every reference for &nbsp;God, including pronouns, titles etc; a cross for &nbsp;Jesus including pronouns; a line for any reference to man, including flesh and body and words like them; a heart around every reference for&nbsp;youor any follower of Christ, including descriptors and plural pronouns; a down arrow for &nbsp;death and words like it, and an up arrow for &nbsp;life and words like it.
	
				&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Romans+6%3A4-14&amp;version=NIV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Romans 6:4-14 NIV</a>
    
		
		
			
				
          
						God
					
          
						Christ
					
          
		  man/body/flesh
					
				
						Noah/you
					
        
						death
					
        
						life
					
				
			
			
				
					
					4 We were therefore buried with him through baptism into death in order that, just as Christ was raised from the dead through the glory of the Father, we too may live a new life.
					
					
             5&nbsp;For if we have been united with him in a death like his, we will certainly also be united with him in a resurrection like his.
            6&nbsp;For we know that our old self was crucified with him so that the body ruled by sin might be done away with, that we should no longer be slaves to sin— 7&nbsp;because anyone who has died has been set free from sin.
            
    		
8&nbsp;Now if we died with Christ, we believe that we will also live with him. 9&nbsp;For we know that since Christ was raised from the dead, he cannot die again; death no longer has mastery over him. 10&nbsp;The death he died, he died to sin once for all; but the life he lives, he lives to God. 11&nbsp;In the same way, count yourselves dead to sin but alive to God in Christ Jesus. 


12&nbsp;Therefore do not let sin reign in your mortal body so that you obey its evil desires. 13&nbsp;Do not offer any part of yourself to sin as an instrument of wickedness, but rather offer yourselves to God as those who have been brought from death to life; and offer every part of yourself to him as an instrument of righteousness. 14&nbsp;For sin shall no longer be your master, because you are not under the law, but under grace.

        
			
		
  
  					&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Romans+6%3A4-14&amp;version=NIV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Romans 6:4-14 NIV</a>
    
 
  Please do your best to answer the questions as simply as you can based on the text given and not any prior knowledge you may have, even if it's biblical. <br><br>Questions with asterisks* may inquire about general definitions and meaning not found in the text, for those you may use your common knowledge.

  
<br>
<br>What are the connections Paul is making between the baptism of repentance (John's baptism) and Christ's death and rising from the dead? (6:4)
<br>Going into the water in baptism is a symbol of what based on what?
<br>What is the glory of the Father that raised Christ from the dead?*
<br>Verse 6:4 says, We were buried with Him through baptism into death. If the glory of the Father raised Christ from the dead, how are we able to live a new life after our death with Him? (6:4)
<br>According to 6:5, what benefit is there in our union with Him?
<br>According to 6:6, what benefit is there in our union with Him?
<br>According to the text, what exchanges are being made in our union with Christ? (6:5-8)
<br>What does it mean for us to die with Christ? (6:7)
<br>Verse 6:8 says, Now if we died with Christ, we believe that we will also live with him. What does it mean for us to live with Christ according to verse (6:10)?
<br>If we died with Him, does that mean that we are dead to sin once and for all? (6:10)
<br>6:14 says, Sin shall no longer be your master, how was that mastery removed (6:8-9) and what do you have to do to maintain it? (6:13)
<br>In this scripture, is the new life for us referring to our lives now or life after death? What part of the text supports that?
<br>&nbsp;<br><br>
    
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Romans+6%3A4-14&amp;version=NIV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Romans 6:4-14 NIV</a>
    
  
<br>
<br>If being under the law makes sin your master, what can verse 6:14 imply that grace allows you to do?
<br>6:5 refers to what we have going on with Christ as a union. In what ways is our connection with Christ like a marriage?
<br>What does Christ get out of it?
<br>In what ways does the single life reflect the life before Christ and the married life reflect the life with Christ?
<br>What are some positive practical things that a spouse can bring to a marriage?
<br>What are some negative practical things that a spouse can bring to a marriage?
<br>Is there any way to avoid exposure to these things?
<br>Should anything be avoided in the union of husband and wife?
]]></description><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/the-kings-college/concept-1/concept-1-unit-4.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">the-kings-college/Concept 1/Concept 1 - Unit 4.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aleeza Chery]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:16:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Concept 1 - Unit 5]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br> Clean &amp; Pure: An Introduction to Soul Care - Concept 1 - The Proposal
	
    		
    Acts 18:24-19:12 ESV
  
<br><br>Apostle Paul's radical conversion from Pharisee to devout follower of the way of Christ is one of the reasons he is a revered figure in the hall of faith. However, it is his perseverance with joy that is so astonishing to read.<br>Luke, a physician who did not walk with Christ but traveled with Paul, writes his version of the gospel using interviews and he also writes the book of acts as a companion of Paul and is attributed to writing 27% of the new testament. In this chapter of Acts, that we are about to read, Luke recalls an encounter of apostle Paul with a group of Jesus followers.<br>While reading this passage, we will put a triangle for every reference for &nbsp;God, including pronouns; a cross for &nbsp;Jesus including pronouns; a circle for every reference of the &nbsp;Holy Spirit; a heart around every reference for &nbsp;you or any followers of Christ, including descriptors and plural pronouns, and a star for &nbsp;unbelievers/potential believers.
	
				&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Acts+19%3A1-12&amp;version=ESV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Acts 18:24-19:12 ESV</a>
    
		
		
			
				
					
						God
					
					
						Christ
					
          
						Holy Spirit
					
				
						you / follower
					
        
						unbeliever/<br>potential believer
					
				
			
			
				
					
					18
            24 Now a Jew named Apollos, a native of Alexandria, came to Ephesus. He was an eloquent man, competent in the Scriptures. 25 He had been instructed in the way of the Lord. And being fervent in spirit, he spoke and taught accurately the things concerning Jesus, though he knew only the baptism of John. 26 He began to speak boldly in the synagogue, but when Priscilla and Aquila heard him, they took him aside and explained to him the way of God more accurately. 27 And when he wished to cross to Achaia, the brothers encouraged him and wrote to the disciples to welcome him. When he arrived, he greatly helped those who through grace had believed, 28 for he powerfully refuted the Jews in public, showing by the Scriptures that the Christ was Jesus.
					
					
										19
            1 And it happened that while Apollos was at Corinth, Paul passed through the inland country and came to Ephesus. There he found some disciples. 2 And he said to them, “Did you receive the Holy Spirit when you believed?” And they said, “No, we have not even heard that there is a Holy Spirit.” 3 And he said, “Into what then were you baptized?” They said, “Into John's baptism.” 4 And Paul said, “John baptized with the baptism of repentance, telling the people to believe in the one who was to come after him, that is, Jesus.” 5 On hearing this, they were baptized in the name of the Lord Jesus. 6 And when Paul had laid his hands on them, the Holy Spirit came on them, and they began speaking in tongues and prophesying. 7 There were about twelve men in all.
					
					
            8 And he entered the synagogue and for three months spoke boldly, reasoning and persuading them about the kingdom of God. 9 But when some became stubborn and continued in unbelief, speaking evil of the Way before the congregation, he withdrew from them and took the disciples with him, reasoning daily in the hall of Tyrannus. 10 This continued for two years, so that all the residents of Asia heard the word of the Lord, both Jews and Greeks.
            
    		
          11 And God was doing extraordinary miracles by the hands of Paul, 12 so that even handkerchiefs or aprons that had touched his skin were carried away to the sick, and their diseases left them and the evil spirits came out of them. 

        
			
		
  
  					&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Acts+19%3A1-12&amp;version=ESV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Acts 18:24-19:12 ESV</a>
    
 
  Please do your best to answer the questions as simply as you can based on the text given and not any prior knowledge you may have, even if it's biblical. <br><br>Questions with asterisks* may inquire about general definitions and meaning not found in the text, for those you may use your common knowledge.

  
<br>
<br>
Can God use you if you don't have a full understanding of the Kingdom?

<br>
Can you be a disciple or follower of Christ without the baptism of the Holy Spirit?

<br>
How was Apollos corrected on what he was believing and teaching?

<br>
What does Apollos' correction do for his ministry?

<br>
What baptism were the disciples in this passage baptized with before they met Paul?

<br>
What does this passage let us know about the baptism of repentance also known as John's baptism?

<br>
At what point did the disciples receive the Holy Spirit?

<br>
We talked about Jesus' baptism (or the baptism of the Holy Spirit and of fire) previously, what does it produce in Paul and the disciples?

<br>
Is the only evidence of the Holy Spirit supernatural gift in this passage?

<br>
What other evidence is there of the Holy Spirit in this text besides tongues and prophesying?

<br>
Does having the Holy Spirit make things easier for Paul and the disciples according to this passage? 

<br>
What does the passage of time tell us about the perseverance of Paul and the disciples?

<br>&nbsp;<br><br>
    
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Acts+19%3A1-12&amp;version=ESV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Acts 18:24-19:12 ESV</a>
    
  
<br>
<br>
Does Paul and the disciples' perseverance have anything to do with the Holy Spirit?

<br>
According to what happened with Apollos and the disciples, What is the importance of remaining teachable?

<br>
What potentially do the men in the synagogue miss out on because of their stubbornness?

<br>
If someone knew you before you were married and after you married, the friend regarded you as single, how would you feel about that? How can this inform what it could mean to regard no one according to the flesh?

]]></description><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/the-kings-college/concept-1/concept-1-unit-5.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">the-kings-college/Concept 1/Concept 1 - Unit 5.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aleeza Chery]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:16:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Concept 1 - Unit 6]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br> Clean &amp; Pure: An Introduction to Soul Care - Concept 1 - The Proposal
	
    		
    2 Corinthians 5:14-21 HCSB;NASB
  
<br><br>We are referencing another first century letter from Apostle Paul, who, this time is writing his second letter to the the congregation members in the city of Corinth, Ancient Greece. He is defending himself because they don't believe he can be a Spirit-filled apostle because of his many sufferings.<br>While reading this passage, we will put a triangle for every reference for &nbsp;God, including pronouns; a cross for &nbsp;Jesus including pronouns; a circle for every reference of the &nbsp;Holy Spirit; a line for any reference to the flesh; a heart around every reference for &nbsp;you or any followers of Christ, including descriptors and plural pronouns, and a star for &nbsp;unbelievers/potential believers.
	
				&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=2%20Corinthians%205%3A14-21&amp;version=HCSB;NASB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2 Corinthians 5:14-21 HCSB;NASB</a>
    
		
		
			
				
					
						God
					
					
						Christ
					
          
						Holy Spirit
					
				
						you / follower
					
          
		  flesh
					
        
						unbeliever/<br>potential believer
					
				
			
			
				
					
					5
            14 For Christ’s love compels us, since we have reached this conclusion: If One died for all, then all died. 15 And He died for all so that those who live should no longer live for themselves, but for the One who died for them and was raised.
					
					
            16 Therefore from now on we recognize no one by the flesh; even though we have known Christ by the flesh, yet now we know Him in this way no longer. 17 Therefore if anyone is in Christ, this person is a new creation; the old things passed away; behold, new things have come. 18 Now all these things are from God, who reconciled us to Himself through Christ and gave us the ministry of reconciliation, 19 namely, that God was in Christ reconciling the world to Himself, not counting their wrongdoings against them, and He has committed to us the word of reconciliation.
					
					
            20 Therefore, we are ambassadors for Christ, as though God were making an appeal through us; we beg you on behalf of Christ, be reconciled to God. 21 He made Him who knew no sin to be sin in our behalf, so that we might become the righteousness of God in Him.
            
        
			
		
  
  					&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=2%20Corinthians%205%3A14-21&amp;version=HCSB;NASB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2 Corinthians 5:14-21 HCSB;NASB</a>
    
 
  Please do your best to answer the questions as simply as you can based on the text given and not any prior knowledge you may have, even if it's biblical. <br><br>Questions with asterisks* may inquire about general definitions and meaning not found in the text, for those you may use your common knowledge.

  
<br>
<br>
Thinking about the steps and symbols of baptism, How does it illustrate being a new creation?

<br>
What is the importance of the love mentioned in verse 14?

<br>
Who does those who live refer to in verse 15?

<br>
What does should no longer live for themselves, but for the One who died for them and was raised mean in verse 15?

<br>
What is 16 saying about the flesh? “So from now on we regard no one according to the flesh. Even if we have known Christ according to the flesh, we no longer know him in that way.”

<br>
What is 17 saying in response to disregarding the flesh in 16? Therefore if anyone is in Christ, this person is a new creation; the old things passed away; behold, new things have come.

<br>
Does “the newness” in verse 17 correspond to Christ?

<br>&nbsp;<br><br>
    
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=2%20Corinthians%205%3A14-21&amp;version=HCSB;NASB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2 Corinthians 5:14-21 HCSB;NASB</a>
    
  
<br>
<br>
What can love do to a person's drive or motivation to do something?<br>


<br>
Do you have an experience where love drove you to do something outlandish? out of your comfort zone or even out of character?<br>


<br>
What about longevity? Have you endured something for a long length of time because of love for a person?

<br>
Would you say Christ's love have this kind of hold on you yet? In terms of outlandishness and longevity?

]]></description><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/the-kings-college/concept-1/concept-1-unit-6.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">the-kings-college/Concept 1/Concept 1 - Unit 6.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aleeza Chery]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:15:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Concept 1 - Unit 7]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br> Clean &amp; Pure: An Introduction to Soul Care - Concept 1 - The Proposal
	
    		
    John 21:1-22 Various Translations
  
<br><br>Out of all the disciples and apostles, Peter and Paul stand out in the scripture for the extraordinary working of the power of God through them. Unlike Paul, Peter was closely acquainted with Jesus, spending 3 years walking alongside Him. Before Christ's death and rising, Peter received many rebukes from Christ despite his zealousness to be loyal. He seemed to be the unintentional troublemaker in the class and when there was no more time to learn and the semester was over, he found out from the Teacher that he would fail the exam that he didn't even take yet, to which he solemnly swore he would step up to the plate and pass. Alas, Peter succumbed to his fear and self-preservation and indeed denies Christ on the day He was captured to be taken to be crucified—and to ensure he was soberly thinking about it—he was given 3 opportunities, but denies Christ at each one.<br>While reading this passage, we will put a triangle for every reference for &nbsp;God, including pronouns; a cross for &nbsp;Jesus including pronouns; a circle for every reference of the &nbsp;Holy Spirit; a heart around every reference for &nbsp;you or any followers of Christ, including descriptors and plural pronouns, and a star for &nbsp;unbelievers/potential believers.
	
				&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=John%2021&amp;version=ESV;HCSB;NASB;NIV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">John 21:1-22 Various Translations</a>
    
		
		
			
				
					
						God
					
					
						Christ
					
          
						Holy Spirit
					
				
						you / follower
					
        
						unbeliever/<br>potential believer
					
				
			
			
				
					
            1 After these things Jesus revealed Himself again to the disciples at the Sea of Tiberias, and He revealed Himself in this way: 2 Simon Peter, Thomas who was called Didymus, Nathanael of Cana in Galilee, the sons of Zebedee, and two others of His disciples were together. 3 Simon Peter *said to them, “I am going fishing.” They *said to him, “We are also coming with you.” They went out and got into the boat; and that night they caught nothing.
					
					
            4 Just as day was breaking, Jesus stood on the shore; yet the disciples did not know that it was Jesus. 5 Jesus said to them, “Children, do you have any fish?” They answered him, “No.” 6 He said to them, “Cast the net on the right side of the boat, and you will find some.” So they cast it, and now they were not able to haul it in, because of the quantity of fish.
					
					
            7 Then the disciple whom Jesus loved said to Peter, “It is the Lord!” As soon as Simon Peter heard him say, “It is the Lord,” he wrapped his outer garment around him (for he had taken it off) and jumped into the water.8 The other disciples came in the boat, dragging the net full of fish, for they were not far from the land, but about a hundred yards off.
            
          
            9 When they got out on land, they saw a charcoal fire in place, with fish laid out on it, and bread. 10 Jesus said to them, “Bring some of the fish that you have just caught.” 11 So Simon Peter went aboard and hauled the net ashore, full of large fish, 153 of them. And although there were so many, the net was not torn. 
            
          
            12 “Come and have breakfast,” Jesus told them. None of the disciples dared ask Him, “Who are You?” because they knew it was the Lord. 13 Jesus came, took the bread, and gave it to them. He did the same with the fish.
            
          
            14 This was now the third time Jesus appeared to the disciples after He was raised from the dead.
            
          
            15 When they had finished breakfast, Jesus said to Simon Peter, “Simon, son of John, do you love me more than these?” He said to him, “Yes, Lord; you know that I love you.” He said to him, “Feed my lambs.” 16 He said to him a second time, “Simon, son of John, do you love me?” He said to him, “Yes, Lord; you know that I love you.” He said to him, “Tend my sheep.” 17 He said to him the third time, “Simon, son of John, do you love me?” Peter was grieved because he said to him the third time, “Do you love me?” and he said to him, “Lord, you know everything; you know that I love you.” Jesus said to him, “Feed my sheep. 18 Truly, truly, I say to you, when you were young, you used to dress yourself and walk wherever you wanted, but when you are old, you will stretch out your hands, and another will dress you and carry you where you do not want to go.” 19 He said this to signify by what kind of death he would glorify God. After saying this, He told him, “Follow Me!” 
            
            20 So Peter turned around and saw the disciple Jesus loved following them. That disciple was the one who had leaned back against Jesus at the supper and asked, “Lord, who is the one that’s going to betray You?” 21 When Peter saw him, he said to Jesus, “Lord—what about him?” 22 “If I want him to remain until I come,” Jesus answered, “what is that to you? As for you, follow Me.”
          
        
			
		
  
  					&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=John%2021&amp;version=ESV;HCSB;NASB;NIV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">John 21:1-22 Various Translations</a>
    
 
  Please do your best to answer the questions as simply as you can based on the text given and not any prior knowledge you may have, even if it's biblical. <br><br>Questions with asterisks* may inquire about general definitions and meaning not found in the text, for those you may use your common knowledge.

  
<br>
<br>How can you tell, from this text, how Peter feels about Christ before they even speak?
<br>What does Jesus do for them when he appears?
<br>Why do you think they weren't able to fish successfully?
<br>Why do you think Jesus calls them children?
<br>What can verse 11 tell us about what Jesus' presence does for Peter?
<br>Has Peter proven by his actions that he will be a faithful servant, only based on what he has done up to this point? *We are taking into consideration his denial not mentioned in this text.
<br>What can it mean that Peter is chosen after failing so badly (denial) after walking closely with Christ for 3 years?
<br>What does Peter admit the third time Jesus asks him if he loves Him?
<br>If Peter is chosen at this point, without proof of faithfulness, what is Christ looking for? What is he asking Peter?
<br>Does this text prove Peter's commitment or Jesus' commitment? How?
&nbsp;

<br><br>
    
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=John%2021&amp;version=ESV;HCSB;NASB;NIV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">John 21:1-22 Various Translations</a>
    
  
<br>
<br>This is the 3rd time according to the text that Peter has seen Jesus. The previous 2 times, Jesus doesn't mention his betrayal. What could you imagine he feels not hearing Jesus' thoughts on it?
<br>How do you imagine he feels once he does hear it?
<br>Is Jesus asking Peter if he loves Him to find out if it’s true?
<br>Thinking about our previous reflection question,"What can love do to a person's drive or motivation to do something?" What could be Jesus' reason for revealing to Peter the kind of death by which he would glorify God–after asking Peter if he loves him 3 times? (v. 18-19)
<br>According to the exchange in the text between Jesus and Peter, do you think that Peter feels adequate when He's instructed to feed Yeshua's lambs? Can you relate to this?
]]></description><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/the-kings-college/concept-1/concept-1-unit-7.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">the-kings-college/Concept 1/Concept 1 - Unit 7.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aleeza Chery]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:25:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Concept 1 - Unit 8]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br> Clean &amp; Pure: An Introduction to Soul Care - Concept 1 - The Proposal
	
    		
    Ephesians 3:8-19 Various Translations
  
<br><br>Some recognize the book of Ephesians as Paul's general letter, applicable to any church community that expounds on His core and foundational beliefs because some of the earliest manuscripts don't have the greeting in 1:1–which is the only place the name Ephesus is found. This letter is not addressing any moral issues or answering any theological questions. It is a plain foundational doctrine.  Paul carefully dissects this letter into two parts. In part one which covers chapters 1-3, Paul speaks on the underlying foundation of salvation–which is the love and predisposition of the Godhead toward the chosen. Part two is a call to walk out this calling with confidence, assurance, perseverance and determination, which completely depends on part one.<br>While reading this passage, we will put a triangle for every reference for &nbsp;God, including pronouns; a cross for &nbsp;Jesus including pronouns; a circle for every reference of the &nbsp;Holy Spirit; a heart around every reference for &nbsp;you i.e. the church, including descriptors and plural pronouns, an underline for the word heart; and a star for&nbsp;unbelievers/potential believers; , and an up arrow for strength/power.
	
				&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Ephesians%203%3A8-19&amp;version=HCSB;NASB;NIV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ephesians 3:8-19 Various Translations</a>
    
		
		
			
				
					
						God
					
					
						Jesus
					
          
						Spirit
					
				
						you / follower
					
        
						heart
					
	
						unbeliever/<br>potential believer
					
	
						strength/power
					
				
			
			
				
					
            8 To me, the very least of all saints, this grace was given, to preach to the Gentiles the unfathomable riches of Christ,  9&nbsp;and to enlighten all people as to what the plan of the mystery is which for ages has been hidden in God, who created all things; 10 so that the multifaceted wisdom of God might now be made known through the church to the rulers and the authorities in the heavenly places. 11 This is according to His eternal purpose accomplished in the Messiah, Jesus our Lord. 12&nbsp;In Him we have boldness and confident access through faith in Him. 13 So then I ask you not to be discouraged over my afflictions on your behalf, for they are your glory.
					
          
            14 For this reason I kneel before the Father, 15 from whom every family in heaven and on earth derives its name.  16 I pray that out of his glorious riches he may strengthen you with power through his Spirit in your inner being, 17 so that Christ may dwell in your hearts through faith.         
 And I pray that you, being rooted and established in love, 18 may have power, together with all the Lord’s holy people, to grasp how wide and long and high and deep is the love of Christ, 19 and to know this love that surpasses knowledge—that you may be filled to the measure of all the fullness of God. 
            
        
			
		
  
  					&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Ephesians%203%3A8-19&amp;version=HCSB;NASB;NIV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ephesians 3:8-19 Various Translations</a>
    
 
  Please do your best to answer the questions as simply as you can based on the text given and not any prior knowledge you may have, even if it's biblical. <br><br>Questions with asterisks* may inquire about general definitions and meaning not found in the text, for those you may use your common knowledge.

  
<br>
<br>
What does verse 8, along with verse 9 tell us about being chosen to do something for God?

<br>
How does Christ's sacrifice affect our relationship with the Father? (v. 12)

<br>
According to the last paragraph in this text, what does love have to do with power?

<br>&nbsp;<br><br>
    
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Ephesians%203%3A8-19&amp;version=HCSB;NASB;NIV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ephesians 3:8-19 Various Translations</a>
    
  
<br>
<br>
Why do you think it is saying that Christ's love as opposed God's love that fuels this empowerment? (Last paragraph, v. 17b-19)

<br>
What does it mean for someone to dwell in your heart? (v. 17)

<br>
Why do you think that kind of intimacy with Christ is important?

<br>
Verses 16-17 says, "I pray that out of his glorious riches he may strengthen you with power through his Spirit in your inner being,&nbsp;so that Christ may dwell in your hearts through faith." Why do you think it takes a strengthening power for Christ to be able to dwell in your heart?

]]></description><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/the-kings-college/concept-1/concept-1-unit-8.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">the-kings-college/Concept 1/Concept 1 - Unit 8.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aleeza Chery]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 10:43:44 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>