<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Soul Care]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/</link><image><url>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Soul Care</title><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/</link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 18:27:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 18:27:42 GMT</pubDate><copyright><![CDATA[Aleeza Chery]]></copyright><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator>Aleeza Chery</dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Concept 2 - Introduction]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br> Clean &amp; Pure: An Introduction to Soul Care - Concept 2 - The Divorce

		
			Concept 2
		
    
  
<br>We are beings who posses both spirit and flesh; and because of the intertwining of our spirit and flesh, it can be easy for us to become obstructed from executing our faith purely. Understanding the flesh and the protocol for managing it is key for maintaining the victory that we desire to have in our everyday lives. In the introduction to the entire study, we referenced Paul's struggle with the flesh in Romans 7. Paul makes the statement later on in that chapter, "For I know that nothing good dwells in me, that is, in my flesh. For I have the desire to do what is right, but not the ability to carry it out."<br>The purpose of this concept is to make the clear distinction found in scripture between the spirit and flesh and to recognize that the flesh cannot be made into anything that is useful for the Kingdom of God. Morality is not Christianity. In order for us to say yes to the proposal of Christ, we must first have a divorce of our current spouse; the flesh.<br>Once again, let us look at various excerpts of scripture with fresh eyes, to allow this work to be done. Hebrews 4:12 says, “For the word of God is alive and active. Sharper than any double-edged sword, it penetrates even to dividing soul and spirit, joints and marrow; it judges the thoughts and attitudes of the heart.”<br>
  
    Do you remember reading comprehension in grade school? The teacher would give a text and there would be questions after and all of the answers would be pulled from the text? And then if you ever got stuck on a question, the teacher would have you go back to the text? For the purpose of this study–biblical based strengthening of the foundation of our faith–after each reading, there are discussion prompt questions to help us dig deeper, but simply in our understanding of scripture. Please do your best to answer the questions as simply as you can based on the text given and not any prior knowledge you may have, even if it's biblical.
  
]]></description><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/the-kings-college/concept-2/concept-2-introduction.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">the-kings-college/Concept 2/Concept 2 - Introduction.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aleeza Chery]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 17:38:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Concept 2 - Unit 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br> Clean &amp; Pure: An Introduction to Soul Care - Concept 2 - The Divorce
	
    		
    John 2:23-3:21 NASB
  
<br><br>This book of the Gospel of Christ written by John is very different from the other three gospels in many ways; too many to list in this backdrop. John—who is believed to be the closest disciple to Jesus and refers to himself in the writings as the one Jesus loved—focuses on the revelation of who Christ is in his entire identity; especially as the Son of God, and mentions the word believe almost 100 times. This book documents Jesus' 7 “I AM” statements, highlights 7 miracles done by Him, and confirms the witness of 7 persons declaring that He, indeed, is the Son of God. By this chapter, 2, Jesus has already been baptized by water and the Spirit, chosen his disciples and begun his public ministry—where He challenges many schools of thought.<br>For instance, the Pharisees were a self-appointed overseer group in Israel who set up their own laws, nitpicking and monitoring the activities of their fellow Israelis. They emerged in opposition to the Sadducees, the party of the Jewish high priesthood instated by the law of Moses. Pharisees rejected blind adherence to the law if it conflicted with human rationale or conscience. They believed1 “humans must use their reason in interpreting the Torah and [in] applying it to contemporary problems.” We drop in on Jesus' ministry right when he's about to have a conversation with a Pharisee named Nicodemus.<br>
	While reading this passage, we will put a cross for every reference to Jesus, including pronouns or titles; a triangle for every reference for God, including pronouns; a circle for every reference for the Holy Spirit; an up arrow for every reference to being born; a line under flesh, people, man or mankind, and an exclamation mark for believe and words like it.
	
			&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=John%202%3A23-3%3A21&amp;version=NASB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">John 2:23-3:21 NASB</a>
    
		
		
			
				
          
            Jesus
					
					
            God
					
					
            The Spirit
					
					
            born
					
					
            man/flesh
					
					
            believe
					
				
				
					In Numbers 21, the people of Israel, became discouraged and grumbled against God; despising the manna He gave them, while traveling in the desert under His care by way of Moses’ leadership. God sent fiery snakes among them and many died, but God instructed Moses to make a snake sculpture out of brass, set it on a pole so that anyone who was bitten but then looked at the sculpture did not die from the snake bites.
				
			
			
				
          
          
							2
						
						23 Now when He was in Jerusalem at&nbsp;the Passover, during the feast, many believed in His name as they&nbsp;observed His signs which He was doing. 24 But Jesus, on His part, was not entrusting Himself to them, because&nbsp;He knew all people, 25 and because He did not need anyone to testify about mankind,&nbsp;for He Himself knew what was in mankind.
					
					
					
							3
						
						1 Now there was a man of the Pharisees, named&nbsp;Nicodemus, a&nbsp;ruler of the Jews; 2 this man came to Jesus at night and said to Him, “Rabbi, we know that You have come from God as a teacher; for no one can do these signs that You do unless God is with him.” 3 Jesus responded and said to him,&nbsp;“Truly, truly, I say to you, unless someone&nbsp;is born&nbsp;again he cannot see&nbsp;the kingdom of God.”
					
					
						4 Nicodemus *said to Him, “How can a person be born when he is old? He cannot enter his mother’s womb a second time and be born, can he?” 5 Jesus answered,&nbsp;“Truly, truly, I say to you, unless someone is born of&nbsp;water and&nbsp;the&nbsp;Spirit, he cannot enter&nbsp;the kingdom of God. 6 &nbsp;That which has been born of the flesh is flesh, and that which has been born of the Spirit is spirit. 7 &nbsp;Do not be amazed that I said to you, ‘You must be born&nbsp;again.’ 8 The wind blows where it wishes, and you hear the sound of it, but you do not know where it is coming from and where it is going; so is everyone who has been born of the Spirit.”
					
					
            9 Nicodemus responded and said to Him, “How can these things be?” 10 Jesus answered and said to him,&nbsp;“You are&nbsp;the teacher of Israel, and&nbsp;_yet_&nbsp;you do not understand these things? 11 Truly, truly, I say to you,&nbsp;we speak of what we know and&nbsp;testify of what we have seen, and&nbsp;you&nbsp;_people_&nbsp;do not accept our testimony. 12 &nbsp;If I told you earthly things and you do not believe, how will you believe if I tell you heavenly things? 13 No one has ascended into heaven, except&nbsp;He who descended from heaven:&nbsp;the Son of Man. 14 And just as&nbsp;Moses lifted up the serpent in the wilderness , so must&nbsp;the Son of Man&nbsp;be lifted up, 15 so that everyone who&nbsp;believes will&nbsp;have eternal life in Him.
					
					
            16&nbsp;“For God so&nbsp;loved the world, that He&nbsp;gave His&nbsp;only Son, so that everyone who&nbsp;believes in Him will not perish, but have eternal life. 17For God&nbsp;did not send the Son into the world&nbsp;to judge the world, but so that the world might be saved through Him. 18&nbsp;The one who believes in Him is not judged; the one who does not believe has been judged already, because he has not believed in the name of&nbsp;the only Son of God. 19 &nbsp;And this is the judgment, that&nbsp;the Light has come into the world, and people loved the darkness rather than the Light; for&nbsp;their deeds were evil. 20 For everyone who does evil hates the Light, and does not come to the Light, so that his deeds will not be exposed. 21 But the one who&nbsp;practices the truth comes to the Light, so that his deeds will be revealed&nbsp;as having been performed in God.”
					
           
				
			
		
  
			&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=John%202%3A23-3%3A21&amp;version=NASB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">John 2:23-3:21 NASB</a>
    
 
  Please do your best to answer the questions as simply as you can based on the text given and not any prior knowledge you may have, even if it's biblical. <br><br>Questions with asterisks* may inquire about general definitions and meaning not found in the text, for those you may use your common knowledge.

  
<br>
<br>What caused people to believe in Jesus' name at Passover? (2:23)
<br>Using verses 2:23-25, What does it mean that they believed in His name?
<br>In verse 3:5, what is Jesus referring to when He says "born of water and the Spirit"?
<br>According to verse 3:8, Is it possible for someone to discern something about the Kingdom without being born of the Spirit?
<br>What does it mean to hear the sound of the wind? (3:8)
<br>If Nicodemus came to inquire of Jesus because of the signs he performed, why does Jesus say He doesn't "accept His testimony"? (3:11)
<br>What does Jesus refer to Himself as in these scriptures? (3:13, 3:18)
<br>According to 3:2, what does Nicodemus trust Jesus as? Why?
<br>Does believing that Jesus can do miracles the same as believing in Him?
<br>According to what Jesus says about judgment in 3:17-18, what could He be saying about Nicodemus?
<br>According to verse 18, what must Nicodemus believe in order to discern more about the Kingdom?
<br>Does the time of day Nicodemus comes have anything to do with what Christ is saying in 8:19, as a parallel?
<br>What is the criteria for seeing (3:3) and entering (3:5) the Kingdom of God? Are they two different things?
<br>Does the judgment discussed in 3:18-20 have to do with a person’s ability to believe? If not, then why is the judgment being passed?
<br>What clear line is Jesus drawing in 3:6 about being able to interact with the Kingdom of God? “That which has been born of the flesh is flesh, and that which has been born of the Spirit is spirit.”
&nbsp;

<br><br>
    
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=John%202%3A23-3%3A21&amp;version=NASB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">John 2:23-3:21 NASB</a>
    
  
<br>
<br>Have you ever been confused by something you believed God said? 
<br>Would you say you avoid thinking about things like that or do you ask a multitude of questions like Nicodemus?
]]></description><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/the-kings-college/concept-2/concept-2-unit-1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">the-kings-college/Concept 2/Concept 2 - Unit 1.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aleeza Chery]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 18:29:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Concept 2 - Unit 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br> Clean &amp; Pure: An Introduction to Soul Care - Concept 2 - The Divorce
	
    		
    Romans 6:16-7:6 Various Translations
  
<br><br>(Repeated from Concept 1) This letter written by Paul—his longest in the New Testament—was sent ahead to the city of Rome circa the year AD 57, to a church he had never visited before, to people he didn't know. Some years before this letter, the booming Christian church in Rome, filled with Jewish converts, was emptied by the Roman Emperor Claudius, when he threw all Jews out of Rome because of their quarreling over a leader named, "Chrestus." The exile was short lived and Jews were invited back into the city by the next emperor, but by then the population of the gentile believers in the area had grown.<br>This letter speaks on the differences and issues between Jewish and Gentile Christians. Paul makes many appeals to their spiritual natures to dismiss their national and cultural allegiances, with a desire to see them united in brotherly love. We zone in on Chapter 6, where Paul is discussing what freedom from sin really means.<br>
	While reading this passage, we will put a cross for every reference to Jesus, including pronouns or titles; a triangle for every reference for God, including pronouns; a circle for every reference for the Holy Spirit; a heart for every reference for you or what can be considered you; an up arrow for every reference for life, righteousness and the like ; a line under flesh, or heart; a down arrow for death, sin and the like; a box around law and the like. 
	
			&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/quicksearch/?quicksearch=Romans+6%3A16-7%3A6&amp;version=NASB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Romans 6:16-7:6 NASB</a>
    
		
		
			
				
          
            Jesus
					
					
            God
					
					
            Holy Spirit
					
					
            you
					
					
            life
					
					
            flesh/heart
					
					
            death
					
					
            law
					
				
			
			
				
          
          
							6
						16 Don’t you know that when you offer yourselves to someone as obedient slaves, you are slaves of the one you obey—whether you are slaves to sin, which leads to death, or to obedience, which leads to righteousness? 17&nbsp;But thanks be to God that, though you used to be slaves to sin, you have come to obey from your heart the pattern of teaching that has now claimed your allegiance. 18    You have been set free from sin and have become slaves to righteousness. 19    I am speaking in human terms because of the weakness of your flesh. For just as you presented the parts of your body as slaves to impurity and to lawlessness, resulting in further lawlessness, so now present your body’s parts as slaves to righteousness, resulting in sanctification.
					
					
						20     When you were slaves to sin, you were free from the control of righteousness.  	21     What benefit did you reap at that time from the
things you are now ashamed of? Those things result in death!
But now that you have been set free from sin and have become slaves of God, the benefit you reap leads to holiness, and the result is eternal life. 	22      For the wages of sin is death, but the gift of God is eternal life in Christ Jesus our Lord.
					
					
          
							7
						
						1    Do you not know, brothers and sisters—for I am speaking to those who know the law—that the law has authority over someone only as long as that person lives? 2    For example, by law a married woman is bound to her husband as long as he is alive, but if her husband dies, she is released from the law that binds her to him.    3  So then, if she has sexual relations with another man while her husband is still alive, she is called an adulteress. But if her husband dies, she is released from that law and is not an adulteress if she marries another man.
					
           
						4 So, my brothers and sisters, you also died to the law through the body of Christ, that you might belong to another, to him who was raised from the dead, in order that we might bear fruit for God.
					
					
						5 For while we were in the flesh, the sinful passions, which were brought to light by the Law, were at work in the parts of our body to bear fruit for death.  6 But now we have been released from the law, since we have died to what held us, so that we may serve in the new way of the Spirit and not in the old letter of the law.
					
				
			
		
  
			&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/quicksearch/?quicksearch=Romans+6%3A16-7%3A6&amp;version=NASB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Romans 6:16-7:6 NASB</a>
    
 
  Please do your best to answer the questions as simply as you can based on the text given and not any prior knowledge you may have, even if it's biblical. <br><br>Questions with asterisks* may inquire about general definitions and meaning not found in the text, for those you may use your common knowledge.

  
<br>
<br>According to verse 6:17, where does true obedience come from?
<br>According to 6:16, what do you do to become the slave, even before you obey?
<br>According to verse 6:18, does freedom end slavery?
<br>Who does the law have authority over? (7:1)
<br>In verse 7:4, what has to happen in order for us to belong to another because of the law?
<br>Verse 7:4 says, you also died to the law through the body of Christ, that you might belong to another, to him who was raised from the dead... In the analogy in verses 7:1-3 about marriage and adultery, who would Christ be according to verse 7:4?
<br>Who would you be in the analogy in verses 7:1-3 according to verse 7:4 you also died to the law through the body of Christ?
<br>What do we produce when we belong to Christ (7:4)?
<br>Staying with the marriage analogy in 7:1-3, if there is offspring produced from being in Christ, who is the old husband according to verse 7:5?
<br>What was the offspring produced from the old marriage according to verse 7:5?
<br>According to the text (7:4-6) Can obeying the law produce fruit for God?
<br>According to verse 7:6, who must we obey to produce fruit for God?
<br>What are the benefits of slavery to God? (6:22)
<br>Going back to the very beginning of this text, how do you become a slave of God?
<br>If a person is not a slave to God, who are they a slave to according to verse 6:16?
<br>Looking again to the marriage analogy in 7:1-3, can we be in Christ and in the flesh at the same time?
<br>Is it possible to bear fruit for God without dying to the flesh and being in Christ?
&nbsp;

<br><br>
    
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/quicksearch/?quicksearch=Romans+6%3A16-7%3A6&amp;version=NASB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Romans 6:16-7:6 NASB</a>
    
  
<br>
<br>According to what was in the scripture referenced, is there any benefit in using the law for sanctification?
<br>In the example above the term adultery is used to describe being under the law, what feeling does that produce in you to think about it that way?
]]></description><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/the-kings-college/concept-2/concept-2-unit-2.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">the-kings-college/Concept 2/Concept 2 - Unit 2.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aleeza Chery]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 20:15:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Concept 2 - Unit 3]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br> Clean &amp; Pure: An Introduction to Soul Care - Concept 2 - The Divorce
	
    		
    Romans 7:7-8:17 NASB
  
<br><br>In the interest of offering an explanation for splitting chapters in our readings, this backdrop will focus primarily on the onset of chapters and verses used to classify scripture. Chapters and verses, which are not present in any original manuscripts of scripture were added for easier indexing. In 1205, thou he was not the first, Dominican, Stephen Langton created the chapter divisions which are used today.<br>By the mid-16th century, editors brought in smaller, verse divisions, largely inspired by Jewish scriptural texts, whose units were implemented using special Hebrew letters and punctuation.<br>Jewish scriptural text, however, utilize about 116 more verse breaks as it concerns the Old Testament, because of they way the Psalms are divided.<br>As it concerns the New Testament, Italian Dominican biblical scholar, Santes Pagnino is credited as the first to implement versification there, but his version was not widely adopted–his divisions were very long. The verse divisions that are widely used today were created in 1151 by French printer Robert Estienne.<br>As described in our previous reading for this concept, this letter written by Paul speaks on the differences and issues between Jewish and Gentile Christians. Paul makes many appeals to their spiritual natures desiring to see them united in brotherly love.<br>We zone in on Chapter 7, where Paul breaks down the mechanisms operating within the system of the human being as it concerns: the law, sin, the flesh and the spirit.<br>
	While reading this passage, we will put a cross for every reference to Jesus, including pronouns or titles; a triangle for every reference for God, including pronouns; a circle for every reference for the the Spirit/spirit; a heart for every reference for believers; an up arrow for every reference for life, righteousness and the like; a line under &nbsp;flesh, or body and the like; a down arrow for death, sin and the like; a box around law; a squiggly line for&nbsp;commandment, and this symbol for good.
	
			&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/quicksearch/?quicksearch=Romans+7%3A7-8%3A17&amp;version=NASB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Romans 7:7-8:17 NASB</a>
    
		
		
			
				
          
            Jesus
					
					
            God
					
					
            The Spirit
					
					
            believers
					
					
            life
					
					
            flesh/body
					
					
            death
					
					
            law
					
					
            commandment
					
					
            good
					
				
				In the Greek, the word condemnation does not mean an expression of strong disapproval instead it refers to the penalty or sentencing for the act that was disapproved of. It would more accurately read, "penalty," "punishment" or  "sentence."
			
			
				
          
          
							7
						7 What shall we say then? Is the Law sin? Far from it! On the contrary, I would not have come to know sin except through the Law; for I would not have known about coveting if the Law had not said, “You shall not covet.” 8 But sin, taking an opportunity through the commandment, produced in me coveting of every kind; for apart from the Law sin is dead. 9 I was once alive apart from the Law; but when the commandment came, sin came to life, and I died; 10 and this commandment, which was to result in life, proved to result in death for me; 11 for sin, taking an opportunity through the commandment, deceived me, and through it, killed me. 12 So then, the Law is holy, and the commandment is holy and righteous and good.
					
					
						13 Therefore did that which is good become a cause of death for me? Far from it! Rather it was sin, in order that it might be shown to be sin by bringing about my death through that which is good, so that through the commandment sin would become utterly sinful.
					
					
						14 For we know that the Law is spiritual, but I am fleshly, sold into bondage to sin. 15 For I do not understand what I am doing; for I am not practicing what I want to do, but I do the very thing I hate. 16 However, if I do the very thing I do not want to do, I agree with the Law, that the Law is good. 17 But now, no longer am I the one doing it, but sin that dwells in me. 18 For I know that good does not dwell in me, that is, in my flesh; for the willing is present in me, but the doing of the good is not. 19 For the good that I want, I do not do, but I practice the very evil that I do not want. 20 But if I do the very thing I do not want, I am no longer the one doing it, but sin that dwells in me.
					
					
						21 I find then the principle that evil is present in me, the one who wants to do good. 22 For I joyfully agree with the law of God in the inner person, 23 but I see a different law in the parts of my body waging war against the law of my mind, and making me a prisoner of the law of sin, the law which is in my body’s parts. 24 Wretched man that I am! Who will set me free from the body of this death? 25 Thanks be to God through Jesus Christ our Lord!
					
					
            
							8
            
            So then, on the one hand I myself with my mind am serving the law of God, but on the other, with my flesh the law of sin.1 Therefore there is now no condemnation at all for those who are in Christ Jesus*. 2 For the law of the Spirit of life in Christ Jesus has set you free from the law of sin and of death.
          
          
            3 For what the Law could not do, weak as it was through the flesh, God did: sending His own Son in the likeness of sinful flesh and as an offering for sin, He condemned sin in the flesh, 4 so that the requirement of the Law might be fulfilled in us who do not walk according to the flesh but according to the Spirit. 5 For those who are in accord with the flesh set their minds on the things of the flesh, but those who are in accord with the Spirit, the things of the Spirit. 6 For the mind set on the flesh is death, but the mind set on the Spirit is life and peace, 7 because the mind set on the flesh is hostile toward God; for it does not subject itself to the law of God, for it is not even able to do so, 8 and those who are in the flesh cannot please God.
					
					
						9 However, you are not in the flesh but in the Spirit, if indeed the Spirit of God dwells in you. But if anyone does not have the Spirit of Christ, he does not belong to Him. 10 If Christ is in you, though the body is dead because of sin, yet the spirit is alive because of righteousness. 11 But if the Spirit of Him who raised Jesus from the dead dwells in you, He who raised Christ Jesus from the dead will also give life to your mortal bodies through His Spirit who dwells in you.
					
					
            12 So then, brothers and sisters, we are under obligation, not to the flesh, to live according to the flesh— 13 for if you are living in accord with the flesh, you are going to die; but if by the Spirit you are putting to death the deeds of the body, you will live. 14 For all who are being led by the Spirit of God, these are sons and daughters of God. 15 For you have not received a spirit of slavery leading to fear again, but you have received a spirit of adoption as sons and daughters by which we cry out, “Abba! Father!” 16 The Spirit Himself testifies with our spirit that we are children of God, 17 and if children, heirs also, heirs of God and fellow heirs with Christ, if indeed we suffer with Him so that we may also be glorified with Him.
          
          * The well know clause usually found in this verse is not found here in the earliest manuscripts of this letter, instead it is found in verse 4 where it also occurs. Scholars do not agree on whether this was error by the scribes or intentional by authorities who did not want Paul's words to be taken out of context.
				
			
		
  
			&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/quicksearch/?quicksearch=Romans+7%3A7-8%3A17&amp;version=NASB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Romans 7:7-8:17 NASB</a>
    
 
  Please do your best to answer the questions as simply as you can based on the text given and not any prior knowledge you may have, even if it's biblical. <br><br>Questions with asterisks* may inquire about general definitions and meaning not found in the text, for those you may use your common knowledge.

  
<br>
<br>What is used to produce the desire to sin?&nbsp;(7:8)
<br>What are the other two laws at work described in this text?&nbsp;(8:2)
<br>If the law is the written commands of God given by Moses, what is the law of the Spirit of life?
<br>What does it mean to "walk according to"?&nbsp;(8:4)
<br>From our previous scripture's text,&nbsp;(6:16-7:6), what do you become to whom you obey?
<br>In&nbsp;(7:9), what does it mean that "I died" in that verse?
<br>What caused the death?
<br>According to 7:11, what has to happen first in order for sin to do the killing and come alive?&nbsp;(7:11)
<br>If deception/misleading is involved, what kind of desires would you say the flesh has? natural desires? evil desires? something else?*
<br>What does it mean to have a mind that is set on the flesh?&nbsp;(8:5)
<br>What does "living in accord with the flesh" mean?&nbsp;(8:13)
<br>Can the flesh be put into submission?&nbsp;(8:7-8)
<br>After reading this scripture, once sin is activated or made alive in the flesh, can it be removed from the flesh?
<br>Thinking about the aside marked with a red asterisk, If condemn used here is referring to sentencing what can it mean that sin in condemned in the flesh?
<br>Does Jesus eradicate sin in a believer with the sacrifice He made?
<br>Where does sin reside?
<br>According to&nbsp;(8:10), what causes the Spirit to live?
<br>According to&nbsp;(8:10), what do you need in you to produce this righteousness?
<br>If Christ was born in the likeness of sinful flesh, does that mean he was sinful?&nbsp;(8:3)
<br>Hebrews 4:14-15&nbsp;says,&nbsp;Since then we have a great high priest who has passed through the heavens, Jesus, the Son of God, let us hold fast our confession. For we do not have a high priest who is unable to sympathize with our weaknesses, but one who in every respect has been tempted as we are, yet without sin.&nbsp;According to our text, Romans 7:7-8:17, How do you think He was able to remain sinless even though He was born in the likeness of sinful flesh?
<br>How is the righteous standard of the law fulfilled in us?&nbsp;(8:4)
<br>What is a product of the mind set on the Spirit?&nbsp;(8:6)
&nbsp;

<br><br>
    
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/quicksearch/?quicksearch=Romans+7%3A7-8%3A17&amp;version=NASB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Romans 7:7-8:17 NASB</a>
    
  
<br>
<br>Is it possible to remain in the Spirit and not come out? How?
]]></description><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/the-kings-college/concept-2/concept-2-unit-3.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">the-kings-college/Concept 2/Concept 2 - Unit 3.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aleeza Chery]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 11:12:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Concept 2 - Unit 3 - Exercise 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br> Clean &amp; Pure: An Introduction to Soul Care - Concept 2 - The Divorce
	
    		
    Romans 7:7-8:17 NASB
  
<br><br>In writing it is easy to go back and forth between time and space to make a point. For the sake of understanding, verse by verse, we will untangle what Paul is saying into short simple statements.<br>
This may be challenging at first because every word will not be included in the simple short statements, just the meat of the meaning.<br>
				Example
			

  
    
      
        7
	
	7 What shall we say then? Is the Law sin? Far from it! On the contrary, I would not have come to know sin except through the Law; for I would not have known about coveting if the Law had not said, “You shall not covet.”
   



				7:7
			
			
				The law is not sin
			
			
				The law makes sin known
			<br>
  
    
      
        7
	
	8 But sin, taking an opportunity through the commandment, produced in me coveting of every kind; for apart from the Law sin is dead.
   



	7:8
			
			
				Sin used the commandment to produce sin in a person
			
			
        Sin is dead if there's no law<br>
      
      
        7
	
	9 I was once alive apart from the Law; but when the commandment came, sin came to life, and I died; 
   

<br>
					7:9
				
				
					A person is alive
				
				
					The commandment was given
				
				
					Sin came to life
				
				
					The person died
				
			
      
      
        7
	
	10 and this commandment, which was to result in life, proved to result in death for me; 
   


				
					7:10
				
				
					The law is intended to result in life
				
		
      
      
        7
	
	11 for sin, taking an opportunity through the commandment, deceived me, and through it, killed me. 
   


				
					7:11
				
				
					Sin deceived the person
				
				
					Sin killed the person
				
		
      
      
        7
	
	12 So then, the Law is holy, and the commandment is holy and righteous and good.
   


				
					7:12
				
				
					The law and it's commandments are holy
				
				
					The commandments of the law are holy righteous and good
				<br><br><br><br>Continue through to the rest of the reading, Romans 7:13-8:17. We will use the simple sentences in another exercise to further bring clarity to the concept Paul is expounding on in this letter.]]></description><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/the-kings-college/concept-2/concept-2-unit-3-exercise-1.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">the-kings-college/Concept 2/Concept 2 - Unit 3 - Exercise 1.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aleeza Chery]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 12:00:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Concept 2 - Unit 3 - Exercise 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br> Clean &amp; Pure: An Introduction to Soul Care - Concept 2 - The Divorce


Romans 7:7-8:17 NASB

<br><br>In writing it is easy to go back and forth between time and space to make a point.<br>For the sake of understanding, verse by verse, we will untangle what Paul is saying into short simple statements. <br>We will use questions to pull the simple statements from the text to get to the meat of the meaning. <br>Implicit Meaning: At times, the implicit meaning may have to be stated, which can get tricky, but the most important part is to keep it as simple and true to the text as possible.<br>Note
There's a version of this Exercise without the Question Prompts. <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Concept 2 - Unit 3 - Exercise 1" data-href="Concept 2 - Unit 3 - Exercise 1" href="https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/the-kings-college/concept-2/concept-2-unit-3-exercise-1.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Make It Plain Exercise Without Question Prompts</a>
<br><br><br><br>
	
	Example
	
	
		
			
				
					7
				
				7 What shall we say then? Is the Law sin? Far from it! On the contrary, I would not have come to know sin except through the Law; for I would not have known about coveting if the Law had not said, “You shall not covet.”
			
		
	
	 7:7 
	
		 Is the law sin?
		Not: No. 
		Good answer: The law is not sin 
	
	
		 What makes sin known?
		Not: The Law. 
		 Good answer: The law makes sin known.
	



	Try It




7

8 But sin, taking an opportunity through the commandment, produced in me coveting of every kind; for apart from the Law sin is dead.




7:8


What used the command to produce sin in a person?
What is the status of sin if there is no law?
<br>
	
	Example
	
	
		
			
				
					7
				
				9 I was once alive apart from the Law; but when the commandment came, sin came to life, and I died;
			
		
	
	 7:9 
	
		A person is alive in what sense?
	A person is alive spirituallyThe word spiritually is not in the text, but seeing as the person dies, but still is moving and breathing, it is implicit that it is a spiritual living and dying is implied. - see Implicit Meaning in the instructions.  
	
	What was given that made it possible for sin to come to life?
	The commandment was give which made it possible for sin to come to life 
					The commandment was givenThe instructions ask for us to use complete sentences. Sometimes in order for the question to draw out the correct response, more context is needed in the question that may not need to be included in the complete sentence. Shorter is usually better unless it changes the meaning.
				
				What happened when the commandment was given?
				
					Sin came to life
				
				
				
					The person diedSometimes one question has two answers.
				

Continue through to the rest of the reading, Romans 7:10-8:17. We will use the simple sentences in another exercise to further bring clarity to the concept Paul is expounding on in this letter.

<br><br>What did the law promise?<br>
What was the actual outcome of the law?<br><br>What 2 things did the law do to the person?<br><br>What is holy?<br>
What are righteous and good?<br><br>What causes death for a person?<br>
What does the commandment do to sin?<br>
What does death through the commandment show?<br><br>What do believers know about the law?<br>
What is the person made of?<br>
What does it mean that a person is sold under sin?<br><br>Does a believer understand their own actions?<br>
What does a believer want to do?<br>
What does a believer end up doing?<br>
What does the believer hate?<br><br>Does a believer want to sin?<br>
Does a believer agree with the law?<br>
What does the believer believe about the law?<br><br>What causes the believer to do wrong/sin?<br><br>Where are the un-good things found in a believer?<br>
what is a believer desire to do?<br>
Does a believer have the ability to do good with the flesh?<br><br>What is the law that occurs when a believer wants to do right?<br><br>What part of a person agrees with God's law?<br><br>Where does the law of sin dwell?<br>
What does the law of sin do to the believer's mind?<br>
What does the law of sin force a believer to be?<br><br>Who delivers a believer from their body of death?<br>
How does a believer serve the law of God?<br>
How does a believer serve the law of sin?<br><br>Is there any <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="condemnation" data-href="condemnation" href="https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/definitions/condemnation.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">condemnation/penalty</a> for sin for those who are in Christ Jesus?<br><br>What 2 things does the law of the Spirit of life free a believer from in Christ Jesus?<br><br>What was the law weakened by?<br>
What was law not able to do? see (<a data-href="#7 10" href="https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/#7_10" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">7 10</a>)<br>
What did God do that the law could not do? see (<a data-href="#7 10" href="https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/#7_10" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">7 10</a>)<br>
How did God bring life?<br>
Where does Jesus condemn sin?<br><br>What does condemning sin in the flesh allow?<br><br>Who are the ones who set their minds on the things of the flesh?<br>
Who are the ones who set their minds on the things of the spirit?<br><br>What does setting the mind on the flesh bring?<br>
What does setting the mind on the spirit bring?<br><br>How does a mind that is set on the flesh behave towards God?<br>
Does the mind that is set on the flesh submit to God's law?<br>
Can the mind that is set on the flesh submit to God's law?<br><br>Can those who are in the flesh please God?<br><br>If the Spirit of God in a believer what are they in?<br>
If the Spirit of God is in a believer what are they not in?<br>
Does a person belong to Christ if they do not have the Spirit of Christ?<br><br>Why is the body dead?<br>
If Christ is in you then what does the Spirit bring?<br><br>What is the criteria for God giving life to the believer's mortal body?<br><br>Are we indebted?<br>
Who aren't we indebted to?<br>
What would being indebted to the flesh make us do?<br><br>What happens if a person lives according to the flesh?<br>
What does a believer use to put to death the deeds of the body?<br>
What happens if the believer puts to death the deeds of the body?<br><br>Who are sons of God?<br><br>What spirit has the believer NOT received?<br>
What does a spirit of slavery cause?<br>
What spirit has the believer received?<br>
What does the Spirit of adoption give the believer?<br><br>What does the Spirit himself do with a believer's spirit?<br><br>If believers are children of God, what else are they?<br>
If believers are heirs of God, what else are they?<br>
How do children of God achieve the status of being glorified with Christ?]]></description><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/the-kings-college/concept-2/concept-2-unit-3-exercise-2.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">the-kings-college/Concept 2/Concept 2 - Unit 3 - Exercise 2.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aleeza Chery]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 20:35:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Concept 2 - Unit 4]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br> Clean &amp; Pure: An Introduction to Soul Care - Concept 2 - The Divorce
	
    		
    Genesis 1:27-31, 2:15-3:7 ESV
  
<br><br>The word genesis means the origin. Genesis is the first book in the Christian scriptural library referred to as the Bible. It is also the first book in the collection of scripture of the Jewish faith called the Torah. This book is the explanation for the creation of things as we know it and also the origin of the people chosen to display who God is to the world. This book along with Exodus, Leviticus, Number and Deuteronomy, is believed to be written down by Moses–and prior to it's writing down–it's stories were passed down by word of mouth. We zone in on chapter 1 verse 26. The creation is unfolding with YHWH God having already made the earth, moon, stars, sea animals, birds and land creatures. He calls it good, then moves on to His last creation, mankind. To note: In Genesis chapter 2 starting from verse 2, once the overview of creation is given, the story back tracks and gives a more detailed account of the creation of mankind.<br>
    While reading this passage, we will put a triangle for every reference for &nbsp;God, His image, including pronouns, titles etc; a line for any reference to the flesh, including body and words like them; a heart around every reference for&nbsp;Adam or Eve directly, including descriptors and plural pronouns; a down arrow for &nbsp;serpent, death and words like it, and an up arrow for &nbsp;life, good, holy and words like it; a symbol like this for a command, actual commands, and words like it.
	
			&nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Genesis+1%3A26-31%2C+Genesis+2%3A15-Genesis+3%3A7&amp;version=ESV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Genesis 1:26-31, 2:15-3:7 ESV</a>
    
		
		
			
				
          
						God
					
          
		  body/flesh
					
				
						human
					
        
						serpent
					
        
						life
					
					
						command
					
				
				The story has backtracked and Eve has not yet been created.
			
			
				
					
					
							1
						
						26&nbsp;Then God said, “Let us make man in our image, after our likeness. And let them have dominion over the fish of the sea and over the birds of the heavens and over the livestock and over all the earth and over every creeping thing that creeps on the earth.”
					27 So God created man in his own image,<br>in the image of God he created him;<br>male and female he created them.
					
					
             28 And God blessed them. And God said to them, “Be fruitful and multiply and fill the earth and subdue it, and have dominion over the fish of the sea and over the birds of the heavens and over every living thing that moves on the earth.” 29&nbsp;And God said, “Behold, I have given you every plant yielding seed that is on the face of all the earth, and every tree with seed in its fruit. You shall have them for food. 30&nbsp;And to every beast of the earth and to every bird of the heavens and to everything that creeps on the earth, everything that has the breath of life, I have given every green plant for food.” And it was so. 31&nbsp;And God saw everything that he had made, and behold, it was very good. And there was evening and there was morning, the sixth day.
            
    		
			
							2
						
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;15&nbsp;The Lord God took the man and put him in the garden of Eden to work it and keep it. 16 And the Lord God commanded the man, saying, “You may surely eat of every tree of the garden,  17&nbsp;but of the tree of the knowledge of good and evil you shall not eat, for in the day that you eat of it you shall surely die.”


18&nbsp;Then the Lord God said, “It is not good that the man should be alone; I will make him a helper fit for him.” 19 Now out of the ground the Lord God had formed every beast of the field and every bird of the heavens and brought them to the man to see what he would call them. And whatever the man called every living creature, that was its name. 20&nbsp;The man gave names to all livestock and to the birds of the heavens and to every beast of the field. But for Adam there was not found a helper fit for him. 21 So the Lord God caused a deep sleep to fall upon the man, and while he slept took one of his ribs and closed up its place with flesh. 22 And the rib that the Lord God had taken from the man he made into a woman and brought her to the man. 23 Then the man said,


“This at last is bone of my bones<br>
    and flesh of my flesh;<br>
she shall be called Woman,<br>
    because she was taken out of Man.”<br>


	24 Therefore a man shall leave his father and his mother and hold fast to his wife, and they shall become one flesh. 25 And the man and his wife were both naked and were not ashamed.



							3
						
						1 Now the serpent was more crafty than any other beast of the field that the Lord God had made. 
						
						He said to the woman, “Did God actually say, ‘You shall not eat of any tree in the garden’?” 2 And the woman said to the serpent, “We may eat of the fruit of the trees in the garden, 3 but God said, ‘You shall not eat of the fruit of the tree that is in the midst of the garden, neither shall you touch it, lest you die.’” 4 But the serpent said to the woman, “You will not surely die. 5 For God knows that when you eat of it your eyes will be opened, and you will be like God, knowing good and evil.” 6 So when the woman saw that the tree was good for food, and that it was a delight to the eyes, and that the tree was to be desired to make one wise, she took of its fruit and ate, and she also gave some to her husband who was with her, and he ate. 7 Then the eyes of both were opened, and they knew that they were naked. And they sewed fig leaves together and made themselves loincloths.
<br>  &nbsp;
<br><br>
		
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Genesis+1%3A26-31%2C+Genesis+2%3A15-Genesis+3%3A7&amp;version=ESV" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Genesis 1:26-31, 2:15-3:7 ESV</a>
    
 
  Please do your best to answer the questions as simply as you can based on the text given and not any prior knowledge you may have, even if it's biblical. <br><br>Questions with asterisks* may inquire about general definitions and meaning not found in the text, for those you may use your common knowledge.

  
<br>
<br>What does God say about His entire creation once He was done with it? (1:31)
<br>In 1:26, God says, "Let us make man in our image, after our likeness." what could that mean in terms of their purity?
<br>What tasks/purposes does God give to Adam and Eve?
<br>&nbsp;<br><br>
    
<a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/quicksearch/?quicksearch=Romans+7%3A7-8%3A17&amp;version=NASB" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Romans 7:7-8:17 NASB</a>
    
  
<br>
<br>What do you think God thinks of Adam and Eve to give them a task of that caliber?
<br>From the poem given, how do you think Adam feels about Eve?&nbsp;(2:23)
<br>If God calls all of the creation very good (1:31), what would you say about the flesh itself at this time?
<br>At what point do you think sin occurs in this passage?
]]></description><link>https://dependentwell.com/the-kings-college/the-kings-college/concept-2/concept-2-unit-4.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">the-kings-college/Concept 2/Concept 2 - Unit 4.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Aleeza Chery]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 11:10:21 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>